<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="/feed.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en-GB">
  <channel>
    <title>Minutes to Midnight</title>
    <description>A gen X with a straight to the point attitude, I gravitate around duality. Using a mix of instinct and academic learning, I juggle between art and technology in equal measure. Based in Cambridge (UK), I work in web design and sound production.</description>
    <link>https://minutestomidnight.co.uk</link>
    <language>en-GB</language>
    <copyright>https://minutestomidnight.co.uk/credits/#copyright</copyright>
    <atom:link href="https://minutestomidnight.co.uk/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Bullies</title>
        <author>hello@minutestomidnight.co.uk (Simone Silvestroni)</author>
        <description><![CDATA[
          Reflecting on something that should have happened a lot to me, while it never did.
          <hr>
          <p>I've been reading several posts as of recently about awful experiences with bullies during school years, or even earlier. Once again, I'm confronted with the baffling fact that I have never had this in my life, even though I <em>should have</em>. Everything was perfectly aligned for me to be a perfect target. I was a quiet introverted, gentle, good at listening, sometimes good with advice. But I didn't really look masculine—on the contrary, I had a slender slightly androgynous figure—I hated competition, I didn't support any of the popular football teams, didn't participate to sports, didn't care about cars or motorcycles, and was addicted to reading.</p>

<p>Instead, what happened was that bullies <em>respected me</em>. I've never got to the end of this, and never will.</p>

<p>In middle school, at 12, there was a boy classmate who became everyone's punchbag. It was bewildering: he was the tallest, the strongest, and he even had a hint of a beard. Despite all that, one person kickstarted this habit of ridiculing and harassing this kind massive guy. That bully was a girl, two years senior to me. They had a history, predating our class, and for whatever reason she spread this idiotic story about him carrying ticks. Of course it was horseshit, nevertheless most of us believed it, only because she was an aggressive bully.</p>

<p>Have no idea why, but all the bullies and 'charismatic' boys and girls in my school years were the less studious, the less smart. All of them, invariably, have followed the same path in life: they stayed in the small town, repeating what little their parents had done decades earlier, and have become awful people. But I digress.</p>

<p>After months of bullying the sweet giant boy, the bully asked me if I wanted to become her boyfriend. With my typical roundabout way of answering awkward questions, I looked her in the eye, and said:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>No.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>The rejection surprised the girl, slowly turning her constant arrogant attitude into something less noisy. I had never participated into bullying the classmate, however, I unfortunately stood there — silent and indifferent. I don't know why, but my crude and brutal rejection initiated some change. A year later, the sweet giant was free from harassment, now seen as our proud mascotte.</p>

<p>One day, I accepted a role in a 5-a-side summer football tournament. Scoring twice in the first five minutes of the debut match put me under an unnerving spotlight. I knew one of the guys in the other team, by reputation only. He lived in a <em>bad</em> neighbourhood, meaning a place where all the immigrants, from both the south of Italy and what was then known as Jugoslavia, lived. Within my small town, that group of council houses, built on purpose in the barren outskirts, was known with a brazen racist slur.</p>

<p>During the match, a fracas started between a group of opposing players. I stayed back with our goalkeeper, looking annoyed at the scene. After hearing some bullshit, I decided to join the fighting teenagers, and tell the referee what I saw. The outcome was that the guy from the bad neighbourhood, exasperated by my teammates, jumped at us and gave me a slap in the face. Hard. He got a red card for that, but I didn't react. I stood there, frozen, watching him leave the field, head down, the public screaming at him. Bullied, relentlessly, only because his family came from Sicily, automatically considered lazy scroungers, and used as an easy target.</p>

<p>I always wanted to be ignored and left alone by both bullies and charismatic self-appointed thought leaders (where <em>thought</em> is a stretch here), and I achieved that. They either ignored me or nodded distantly, as if I was some sort of figure to be respected, or maybe feared. I don't know what type of image of myself I was projecting. I used to think that I could walk between raindrops, without getting wet. Maybe I've always carried a Unabomber vibe.</p>

          <hr /><p><a href="mailto:hello@minutestomidnight.co.uk?subject=Bullies">Reply via email</a></p>]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2024 12:27:49 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>https://minutestomidnight.co.uk/blog/bullies/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">https://minutestomidnight.co.uk/blog/bullies/</guid>
        <category>Personal</category>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Silence</title>
        <author>hello@minutestomidnight.co.uk (Simone Silvestroni)</author>
        <description><![CDATA[
          Reflecting on the amount of time that I spent without writing new music.
          <hr>
          <p>Over the last few days, I cut a ton of code and content from this website. Removed webmentions, notes, the extra code that littered my templates and posts, and blogroll references to people that I never directly interact with. I follow many more RSS feeds, but I only promote writers that share a real connection with me.</p>

<p>I have a working system that I enjoy using. I don't upgrade Jekyll, my computer is running its last operating system, the whole architecture is stable, smooth, and works well. Third-party software dependencies are close to naught, and I like the style. I'm <em>content</em> with this beautiful brutalist efficient minimalism.</p>

<p>Removing cruft feels nice. Stability is good. However, three years after I released my last EP, where's my follow-up album? I have a ton of music drafts, with a few almost-complete songs. I just refused an offer to play bass with a local songwriter. Talking with a friend we have in common, I said:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Beside logistics, I'm finding myself strangely detached from music. My bass track for Gerald was the first attempt in two years. Really weird. I was convinced that once I'd found a job, the music juice would start flowing again. Instead, I don't feel inspired. I'd love to record a new album but all my ideas and drafts are there, uninviting.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Turns out, removing the daily anxiety of having to find a job isn't a magic recipe to reigniting everything else.</p>

          <hr /><p><a href="mailto:hello@minutestomidnight.co.uk?subject=Silence">Reply via email</a></p>]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2024 13:47:02 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>https://minutestomidnight.co.uk/blog/silence/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">https://minutestomidnight.co.uk/blog/silence/</guid>
        <category>Personal</category>
        <category>Music</category>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Four years</title>
        <author>hello@minutestomidnight.co.uk (Simone Silvestroni)</author>
        <description><![CDATA[
          I didn't realise how this August marks four years since I deleted all my corporate social media accounts.
          <hr>
          <p>It feels like a distant memory. Almost unreal, like it never really happened. Hard to put in words how unimportant that colossal waste of time and energy was.</p>

<p>I'm going to celebrate the forgotten anniversary by collecting my thoughts, and deciding to be more direct, more personal. Reflect more about music, life, daily activities, some glimpse of hope for the future.</p>

          <hr /><p><a href="mailto:hello@minutestomidnight.co.uk?subject=Four%20years">Reply via email</a></p>]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2024 22:20:24 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>https://minutestomidnight.co.uk/blog/four-years/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">https://minutestomidnight.co.uk/blog/four-years/</guid>
        <category>Personal</category>
        <category>Social media</category>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Smaller</title>
        <author>hello@minutestomidnight.co.uk (Simone Silvestroni)</author>
        <description><![CDATA[
          As (para)social media keeps reducing its appeal on me, including the definition of 'Fediverse', I'm also finding the concept of indieweb, in its current techno-ideological form, uninteresting.
          <hr>
          <p>Brief reflection on how my interest in a codified <em>indie</em> web is waning at the speed of light. Two main reasons, neither of which are very original.</p>

<p>First, the Fediverse idea, albeit interesting on paper, is gloriously showing its main flaw: pretty much all their incarnations are mimicking social media, with all the consequent detrimental effects. Doom scrolling, an infinite series of short burst of personal opinions, usually disconnected from one another. Whether siloed or decentralised, the resulting unsearchable ephemerality is not really different from other mainstream corporate incarnations. Alex wrote much deeper considerations about this very topic, in their post <a href="https://alexsirac.com/the-fediverse-and-attention-economy/"><em>The Fediverse and attention economy</em></a>.</p>

<p>Second, I completely lost interest in the Indieweb. I respect the project, and still prefer it to the current corporate web dystopia. However, my initial skepticism was right. Matthew Graybosch put it in words for me recently: we solved the interconnections between people on the internet years ago. RSS has this specific purpose, email serves the rest. All that time spent making this website compatible with webmentions should have been used communicating directly with people. The tools were <em>already there</em>.</p>

<p>I'm going to strip this site of all that cruft. No regrets.</p>

          <hr /><p><a href="mailto:hello@minutestomidnight.co.uk?subject=Smaller">Reply via email</a></p>]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2024 22:56:10 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>https://minutestomidnight.co.uk/blog/smaller/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">https://minutestomidnight.co.uk/blog/smaller/</guid>
        <category>Indieweb</category>
        <category>Personal</category>
        <category>Social media</category>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Leaving the web industry</title>
        <author>hello@minutestomidnight.co.uk (Simone Silvestroni)</author>
        <description><![CDATA[
          I accepted an offer for a permanent job in one of the most prestigious British institutes. To get there, I had to first understand I'm not cut for the web industry anymore.
          <hr>
          <p>After spending almost three frustrating months searching in vain for a new job as a <em>web designer</em>, it finally dawned on me that I was looking for a role that does not exist anymore. I had to morph into something else if I wanted a chance. Change the role, change the CV, change LinkedIn, change terminology, adapt to what recruiters want, accept what companies want.</p>

<p>Ride or die.</p>

<p>Even though I saw this coming, my behaviour was akin to the proverbial ostrich with its head in the sand. I was not okay with being a <em>web developer</em>, for 3 straightforward reasons:</p>

<ul>
  <li>I've always been a crossover between design and development.</li>
  <li>I'm not a full-stack developer.</li>
  <li>I consider the process of modern web building, through ever changing frameworks, ruined beyond the tipping point.</li>
</ul>

<p>Basically, had I been willing to accept working for an industry that I'm no longer fascinated by, what I had to do was either learn—properly—one or more programming languages, along with a couple of frameworks based on said languages, or lie about my skills. Having spent 25 years acquiring competence in multiple disciplines, and shipping exceptional products, meant nothing. Or, as one interviewer told me on Zoom, with a grin:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Ah, so you're a Jack of all trades, master of none.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>I rarely swear online, but <em>fuck you</em>.</p>

<p>I was gutted. Everything I see on the web is bloated, slow and clunky. Spaghetti code is plastered everywhere, with a multitude of "full-stack" developers spending their days trying to pointlessly reproduce Macromedia/Adobe Flash with other means. It's like the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Web_Standards_Project">fight for web standards</a> had never happened. Does anybody here remember <a href="https://minutestomidnight.co.uk/blog/rip-molly-holzschlag/">Molly Holzschlag</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jeffrey_Zeldman">Jeffrey Zeldman</a> and the others? Remember how they said that we would meet again, some sunny day?</p>

<p>The sheer number of websites that are not compliant with accessibility guidelines—which is unacceptable—are competing with those who are unable to validate neither HTML nor CSS. None of these things seem to be important; however, <a href="https://tonsky.me/blog/js-bloat/">filling up everything with megabytes of JavaScript</a> is the indisputable top priority.</p>

<p>I initially came up with a new plan: selling myself as a WordPress developer. People with more than one skill are not attractive anymore? Okay, I'm a <em>specialist</em>, then. It wasn't even a lie: I have almost two decades of experience with the tool, but again: I'm a little shy on PHP. I never learned classes, or how to properly use namespaces. I'm familiar with hooks, and more than capable of building a full-fledged WordPress plugin—but—I don't tick all the boxes, sorry.</p>

<p>Moreover, <em>I don't care about WordPress</em>, so it wouldn't have been genuine. I find all the recent business (and tech) choices by Automattic preposterous at best. The way they've changed the system isn't even worth debating, and it <a href="https://dbushell.com/2024/05/07/modern-wordpress-themes-yikes/">seems like I'm not alone</a>.</p>

<p>After weeks of promising interviews for WordPress roles, I accumulated feedback on how close I was, without making the cut. Probably the runner-up to a thirty-something who knew React, and was okay with using gigabytes of Node modules with a truck of Tailwind classes to build an inaccessible one-page site that <a href="https://meiert.com/en/blog/html-conformance-2023/">wouldn't pass the basic W3C validation test</a>.</p>

<p>Enough with the rant.</p>

<p>I decided to look for a radical alternative: pivoting to a different industry. The idea of leaving behind web development was seriously enticing. After dabbling with NHS job ads for a while, and going as far as considering a gig in catering, something attracted my attention.</p>

<p>It was about a role in IT, as a technician. Something that required tasks like building things—and I mean <em>actual building</em>, not with software—helping other people with their issues, solving problems, coming up with personal initiatives, going outside the office, moving items around town. All this within the University of Cambridge.</p>

<p>Reading the job requirements made me realise something that I've never considered about myself: I've always had a huge fascination for technology, and that predates computers. All my closest relatives were gifted with dexterity and talent in manual labour, which fascinated me to no end. After graduating, my first unpaid job was in a music studio. Besides being the in-house bass player, they required a hands-on attitude, knowledge about how electrical equipment works, and an interest in learning how to maintain, repair, or build hardware.</p>

<p>It didn't end there. In all my jobs, I almost always ended up being the CTO's helping hand, which basically made me an unpaid IT technician all along. That was never a problem: I enjoyed that facet of my work. In fact, I liked it so much that I've never requested a larger slice of the cake. However, my CV and my LinkedIn never reflected this reality, because they were already stuffed with heterogeneous skills.</p>

<p>I applied as Chief IT Technician for the University of Cambridge, reworking my CV in a way that showed how much that part of my work had been enjoyable to me. It almost felt like a side of me had come out of the closet. Weeks later, to my surprise, I received an invite to an online interview with the IT team. I don't think I've ever prepared for an interview so intensely and so focused as I did this time.</p>

<p>It felt different, it felt genuine, it rubbed a part of me that had been ghosted for years. Beside a few exceptions here and there, the last time I actually experienced true joy at the idea of going to work was between 2000 and 2004. It was a time and a place where <a href="https://minutestomidnight.co.uk/blog/joining-playstos/">my diverse skillset was valued</a>: hired as a <em>web designer</em>, the company was quietly pivoting to video game production, hence my music degree and production abilities came handy. At the same time, the CTO took a liking on my IT knowledge, so I spent 4 years working three roles: sound designer, web designer, and assistant IT technician.</p>

<p>The interview went well, besides a doubt on the indecisiveness of one of my answers, which stayed with me afterwards, ballooning to gigantic proportions the following days. To my utter surprise, I received an invite to a second interview, this time in person. The 30-minutes written technical test they gave me ended up being so captivating, it felt like the time passed faster than an episode of <em>Blackadder</em>.</p>

<p>After the test, I was introduced to the team. A well-lit quiet office in the heart of Cambridge, surrounded by culture: two doors down is the laboratory where the electron was discovered. A few hundreds metres away, the place where <a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/bitesize/articles/z4pd382">Crick and Watson announced the discovery of DNA</a>. I was told a decision would materialise a week later.</p>

<p>The day after, they offered me the role.</p>

          <hr /><p><a href="mailto:hello@minutestomidnight.co.uk?subject=Leaving%20the%20web%20industry">Reply via email</a></p>]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 11:57:36 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>https://minutestomidnight.co.uk/blog/leaving-the-web-industry/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">https://minutestomidnight.co.uk/blog/leaving-the-web-industry/</guid>
        <category>Featured</category>
        <category>Personal</category>
        <category>Web development</category>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Endless growth</title>
        <author>hello@minutestomidnight.co.uk (Simone Silvestroni)</author>
        <description><![CDATA[
          Stumbling on a post by an American author that I highly respect reignited my doubts about a dominant growth at all costs culture from the US.
          <hr>
          <p>While expressing my thoughts about <a href="https://minutestomidnight.co.uk/blog/minimalism-as-a-product/">minimalism sold as a product</a>, I indulged on the uncomfortable question if I was biased against the supposed (by myself) American tendency to commodify everything. Back then, the only feedback I got from people living in the US was a passive-aggressive post on Mastodon that ended with a meme, smugly invalidating any opinion about American values that might come from <em>abroad</em>.</p>

<p>A few days ago, on one of my favourite blogs <a href="https://blog.jpnearl.com/2024/04/11/fascinating/"><em>Life Is Such A Sweet Insanity</em></a>, a post about travelling on a budget airline contained the following illuminating thought:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>For some reason, the American mindset is endless growth. Everything must get bigger, everything must get better, and more, more, more, how do you like it, how do you like it. But the truth of the matter is, nothing natural undergoes infinite growth, other than some cancers.<cite>J.P. Wing</cite></p>
</blockquote>

<p>J.P. is an amazing writer, and I share an awful lot of his attitude, fully respecting his opinions the rare times when they don't align with mine. He's American. So here I go again: why most of this growth-at-all-costs destructive culture seems to be coming from there?</p>

<p>I've recently decided to stop reading <em>The Conversation</em>, after two consecutive posts were openly accusing Europe's investors of not doing enough to be more like Silicon Valley. I'm seriously confused: how can anyone really believe, in 2024, that their business model is anything close to being sustainable? The mental slavery that parts of Europe still seems to be having towards the <a href="https://www.wheresyoured.at/the-rot-economy/">rot economy</a> fuelled by a type of capitalism not integral to the continent is truly bewildering.</p>

          <hr /><p><a href="mailto:hello@minutestomidnight.co.uk?subject=Endless%20growth">Reply via email</a></p>]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2024 10:12:04 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>https://minutestomidnight.co.uk/blog/endless-growth/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">https://minutestomidnight.co.uk/blog/endless-growth/</guid>
        <category>Sustainability</category>
        <category>Usa</category>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>More Indieweb Automation</title>
        <author>hello@minutestomidnight.co.uk (Simone Silvestroni)</author>
        <description><![CDATA[
          Follow-up to a <a href="/blog/automation-for-my-blog-publishing-workflow/">previous case study</a> on how I automated my static website publishing workflow. This time, a lean Shortcut script is allowing me to write webmentions in seconds.
          <hr>
          <p>For a while now I've been using notes to send Indieweb webmentions in the form of replies and likes. As these tend to be very short pieces, I thought again about how to bypass the annoying bits in the process of creating a note. When I experimented with Apple's Shortcuts to find ways to expedite my writing workflow, I discovered it can be a pretty powerful tool.</p>

<p>Unlike regular posts, likes and replies only require an URL, a name, and in the case of replies also a bit of written content. Everything else can be inferred automatically (date, file name, creation of the file, tags). That's when I decided to make the creation of a webmention with Jekyll as fast as possible. What I've ended up with is an icon in the Dock that I can click whenever I'm ready to reply or like someone's post. The applet asks me for:</p>

<ul>
  <li>the URL of the post I'm liking or replying to;</li>
  <li>the name of the person that I'm mentioning;</li>
  <li>the title of the post (for likes only).</li>
</ul>

<p>Everything else is created in the Shortcut automation:</p>

<figure>
	<img src="https://minutestomidnight.co.uk/assets/images/indieweb-automation-reply.jpg" alt="Screenshot of the Apple software Shortcuts showing an automation to publish content on my website" width="830" height="855" />
	
</figure>

<p>Similarly to what I've achieved with the previous <em>new post</em> automation, once I input the two required info in pop-up prompts, a file is created, the editor Typora is launched, a Terminal session is launched—and minimised in the Dock—with the proper alias commands to serve the website locally. At that point, I can write my reply and be done with it in a very short time.</p>

<p>After duplicating and adjusting the script for likes, I ended up with 3 automation icons: new post, new reply, new like.</p>

<figure>
	<img src="https://minutestomidnight.co.uk/assets/images/indieweb-automation-dock.jpg" alt="Screenshot of a section of a macOS Dock showing three blue icons for posting, and indieweb replies and likes" width="380" height="204" />
	
</figure>

          <hr /><p><a href="mailto:hello@minutestomidnight.co.uk?subject=More%20Indieweb%20Automation">Reply via email</a></p>]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 20:17:38 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>https://minutestomidnight.co.uk/blog/more-indieweb-automation/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">https://minutestomidnight.co.uk/blog/more-indieweb-automation/</guid>
        <category>Workflow</category>
        <category>Indieweb</category>
        <category>Internet</category>
        <category>Software</category>
        <category>Web development</category>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Re: Blocking Bots</title>
        <author>hello@minutestomidnight.co.uk (Simone Silvestroni)</author>
        <description><![CDATA[
          Inspired by <a href="https://neil-clarke.com/block-the-bots-that-feed-ai-models-by-scraping-your-website/">Neil Clarke</a> and Ethan Marcotte, I moved my list of crawlers to a Jekyll YAML data file, and now use it to compile both the <code>.htaccess</code> and <code>robots.txt</code> files.
          <hr>
          <p>The premise is simple: to opt out of AI bots scraping my website and participate to the ongoing training of LLMs, I used to block a bunch of them via the old and trusted <code>robots.txt</code>. Since a rewrite condition within Apache's <code>.htaccess</code> adds a further level of protection, I went on and created a single data file, writing the logic to use it to feed both files.</p>

<p>Once created <a href="https://github.com/simonesilvestroni/m2m-website/blob/main/_data/bots.yml"><code>bots.yml</code></a> in my Jekyll data directory, I used a loop to iterate through the single items in my <code>robots.liquid</code> source file:</p>

<pre><code>---
layout: none
permalink: /robots.txt
---
{%- for item in site.data.bots -%}
User-agent: {{ item }}
Disallow: /

{%- endfor %}
</code></pre>

<p>The end result after a site build is a <code>/robots.txt</code> file containing the entire list of disallowed bots. The rewrite instructions to block AI crawlers in the <code>.htaccess</code> file are the same as suggested by Ethan. Instead of performing a <code>for</code> loop, I just print them inline within a rewrite condition, separated by a pipe character:</p>

<pre><code># Block bots
&lt;IfModule mod_rewrite.c&gt;
  RewriteEngine on
  RewriteBase /
  RewriteCond %{HTTP_USER_AGENT} ({{ site.data.bots | sort_natural | join: "|" }}) [NC]
  RewriteRule ^ – [F]
&lt;/IfModule&gt;
</code></pre>

<h2 id="redirects">Redirects</h2>

<p>Since I was there, I also optimised the <code>.htaccess.liquid</code> source file by creating a further YAML data file with all my redirects, looping through them in a now neat source file:</p>

<pre><code># Redirects
{%- for item in site.data.redirects %}
Redirect 301 {{ item }}
{%- endfor %}
</code></pre>

          <hr /><p><a href="mailto:hello@minutestomidnight.co.uk?subject=Re:%20Blocking%20Bots">Reply via email</a></p>]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 16:41:26 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>https://minutestomidnight.co.uk/blog/re-blocking-bots/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">https://minutestomidnight.co.uk/blog/re-blocking-bots/</guid>
        <category>Web development</category>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>JSON RSS feed</title>
        <author>hello@minutestomidnight.co.uk (Simone Silvestroni)</author>
        <description><![CDATA[
          I quickly created a JSON feed for this website.
          <hr>
          <p>While setting up <a href="https://echofeed.app">Echo Feed</a> to mirror my blog posts on the fediverse, I've discovered how its capabilities to fetch from RSS were more powerful with a JSON feed rather than my regular XML-based one. It's been a while since I've tinkered with the structure of my Jekyll site, so creating a JSON feed sounded like a nice little challenge.</p>

<p>After studying how the new 1.1 spec works, I put Liquid at work, exploiting all kinds of available site-wide variables, loops, conditionals. The end result is a compiled feed.json file that can be added on Echo Feed to extract different sections of new blog posts. In my case: title, summary, permalink, and the first tag.</p>

<p>Here is the <a href="https://minutestomidnight.co.uk/feed.json">compiled file</a>, while this is the source code:</p>

<pre><code>---
layout: null
---
{
  "version": "https://jsonfeed.org/version/1.1",
  "title": "{{ site.title | xml_escape }}",
  "home_page_url": "{{ "/" | absolute_url }}",
  "feed_url": "{{ "/feed.json" | absolute_url }}",
  "description": {{ site.description | strip_html | jsonify }},
  "icon": "{{ "/assets/images/favicons/apple-touch-icon.png" | absolute_url }}",
  "favicon": "{{ "/favicon.ico" | absolute_url }}",
  "expired": false,
  "authors": [
    {
      "name": "{{ site.author.name }}",
      "url": "{{ site.url }}",
      "avatar": "/assets/images/minutes-to-midnight-portrait.jpg"
    }
  ],
  "items": [
    {%- for post in site.posts limit:site.posts_limit %}
    {
      "title": {{ post.title | jsonify }},
      "date_published": "{{ post.date | date_to_xmlschema }}",
      "date_modified": "{{ post.last_modified_at | date_to_xmlschema }}",
      "id": "{{ post.url | absolute_url | sha1 }}",
      "url": "{{ post.url | absolute_url }}",
      "authors": [
        {
          "name": "{{ site.author.name }}",
          "url": "{{ site.author.url }}",
          "avatar": "/assets/images/minutes-to-midnight-portrait.jpg"
        }
      ],
      "summary": {{ post.summary | strip_html | jsonify }},
      "content_text": {{ post.content | strip_html | strip_newlines | jsonify }},
      "content_html": {{ post.content | strip_newlines | jsonify }},
      "tags": [{%- for tag in post.tags %}"{{ tag }}"{% unless forloop.last %},{% endunless %}{% endfor %}]
    }{%- if forloop.last == false %},{% endif %}
    {%- endfor %}
  ]
}
</code></pre>

<p>I haven't tested the feed with a RSS reader, therefore it's not exposed in any page yet. I'm wondering if RSS readers could have any potential advantages.</p>

          <hr /><p><a href="mailto:hello@minutestomidnight.co.uk?subject=JSON%20RSS%20feed">Reply via email</a></p>]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2024 12:04:41 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>https://minutestomidnight.co.uk/blog/json-rss-feed/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">https://minutestomidnight.co.uk/blog/json-rss-feed/</guid>
        <category>Web development</category>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>People and Blogs</title>
        <author>hello@minutestomidnight.co.uk (Simone Silvestroni)</author>
        <description><![CDATA[
          I was interviewed by Manuel Moreale for the 34<sup>th</sup> edition of his weekly newsletter <em>People and Blogs</em>.
          <hr>
          <blockquote>
  <p>I first connected with Simone via email a couple of years ago and then re-discovered his blog thanks to a link in someone's blogroll. The blogroll on his site is excellent btw, definitely worth checking out and the reason why I'm going to rewrite mine.<cite>Manuel Moreale</cite></p>
</blockquote>

<p><a href="https://manuelmoreale.com/pb-simone-silvestroni" class="cta">Read the interview</a></p>

          <hr /><p><a href="mailto:hello@minutestomidnight.co.uk?subject=People%20and%20Blogs">Reply via email</a></p>]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2024 00:10:07 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>https://minutestomidnight.co.uk/blog/people-and-blogs/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">https://minutestomidnight.co.uk/blog/people-and-blogs/</guid>
        <category>Indieweb</category>
        <category>Interview</category>
        <category>Personal</category>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Mastodon</title>
        <author>hello@minutestomidnight.co.uk (Simone Silvestroni)</author>
        <description><![CDATA[
          I've been slowly withdrawing from the decentralised social network. While the reasons I told myself were all related to mental health, they've suddenly changed.
          <hr>
          <p>No matter how I approach social media, at its core there is a simple truth: in the long term it gets to a point where I stop enjoying it. The fact is, I loved Mastodon when it seemed content with being a nieche. I found amazing people there, a few of which have now become friends.</p>

<p>When <em>broadcasters</em>—the ones with a huge following and near zero reciprocity—started arriving, they brought a massive increase in posts about controversial topics, with no thoughts given to the use of content warnings. I've seen discussions tentatively kickstarted by clickbaits, and brilliant comments annihilating initial insipid posts. All of this was okay: without ever following the self-appointed influencers, I just built better filters, ignored the crap, and moved on.</p>

<p>Until something very different happened. The other day I checked my timeline, stumbling on a post by someone I've been following on the Fediverse for a long time. Even though we have rarely interacted, I've always enjoyed his takes on things. One of those persons with whom I feel a human connection without the need of becoming closer. He was complaining about a verbal aggression, describing the huge disappointment of having to face something like that on Mastodon.</p>

<p>A few hours after checking on him in private, I looked for the thread to see first-hand how it developed. The nasty pile-on of people united like an actual fascist mob, insulting someone who was simply trying to have a respectful debate, was awful to read. Unfortunately, the vicious attacks got to the point where Twitter-like death threats were dropped.</p>

<p>No level of controversy can justify this. It's always possible to disagree, even vehemently, while remaining civil. I thought I left cowards and keyboard warriors behind when I deleted my Twitter and Facebook accounts. Wrong.</p>

<p>My conclusion is simple: I think we solved the need of an online <em>social media</em> long ago, when instant messengers and email allowed both quick and in-depth communication among people, whether one to one or in groups. Blogs and RSS feeds added even more. We didn’t need anything else.</p>

<p>Whether centralised or not, when social networks grow beyond a certain level they end up exposing the same flaws in human beings. I suppose this is the beginning of the end — unless I manage to strictly limit my involvement to musicians and a few friends, there is very little point in investing time there.</p>

          <hr /><p><a href="mailto:hello@minutestomidnight.co.uk?subject=Mastodon">Reply via email</a></p>]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2024 17:07:16 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>https://minutestomidnight.co.uk/blog/mastodon/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">https://minutestomidnight.co.uk/blog/mastodon/</guid>
        <category>Personal</category>
        <category>Social media</category>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Minimalism as a product</title>
        <author>hello@minutestomidnight.co.uk (Simone Silvestroni)</author>
        <description><![CDATA[
          The one where I ask myself if I have a bias that makes me perceive Americans as if they want to commodify everything.
          <hr>
          <p>Stumbled on a "video podcast"<sup id="fnref:1" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote" rel="footnote">1</a></sup> by the people who call themselves <em>The Minimalists</em>. They were debating with Cal Newport about social media. I've noticed once again how almost everything that comes from the United States seems to be carrying a not-so-veiled specific <em>patina</em>. The push to self promote and sell looks relentless to me, like a prepared script. I watched the podcast and sometimes nodded in agreement — however, before I realised, I was struck with the indisputable fact that the ultimate goal seemed to package a product, or whatever that is, that could be later sold for a price.</p>

<p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Minimalism">Minimalism is an old concept</a>, and it's something that I've been practicing for a long time in a way or another, both in the daily life and in my work. Not the set of quasi-cultish rules these modern hipsters have carved in stone. Growing up in a poor family, I learned not to waste things, save money, reuse old stuff out of necessity, thus I've never approached minimalism from a privileged point of view. Being immersed in hyper consumeristic rituals has never been my experience.</p>

<p>The American modern version is clearly fixated on decluttering, but it also comes with a specific aesthetic. Their Instagram-perfect shots of big empty houses, proudly showing very few objects in the obligatory subdued palette, promote a way of life that looks unrealistic and fake. The fabricated social media friendly "free-in-exchange-for-your-email-address" PDF of <em>16 Rules to Declutter Your Life</em> preaches on valid principles, while seemingly reducing them to a bourgeois vision through capitalist lenses.</p>

<p>Such lifestyle is not attainable by normal people. I mean the regular folks who need to go to work, cook their food, do the laundry, maybe some gardening or else — they can't afford to spend buckets of money on few hyped products, buy coffee beans from a remote region in South America that cost half a salary at the point of sale. Above all, they cannot keep their place within a spotless private hospital aesthetic, because they <em>actually live</em> in there. They don't usually give TED talks either, especially not to promote some other form of inspirational American Dream that's great to sell another book.</p>

<p>I'd like to understand how and why I've been having this disconcerting feeling for so long. Am I that biased? When I have an exchange with someone living in the US, and I feel like the other person is <em>not</em> trying to sell me something, or subtly talking about money, their career, or ways to build up wealth, I'm positively surprised. I assume it's not a malicious behaviour, surely many Americans do that without realising. However, I think that the trend must come from an ingrained cultural root.</p>

<p>Supposedly, the entire Western civilisation is to blame, I just happen to have noticed this behaviour from a specific geographic area. For sure I've grown tired of listening to rich privileged people who can't see how transparent is their push to commercialise and make money off anything. I'll close with a quote.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>In a documentary about the [minimalist] movement, “bad” consumption is portrayed by masses of people swarming into big box stores on Black Friday, rushing over one another for the best deals. They are, we're led to understand, slaves to material goods, whereas the people who stay away from mass consumption are independent thinkers, free to enjoy the higher planes of life.<br />
But those people flocking to Walmart and other stores don't necessarily see things that way. To go out and purchase furniture, or an entertainment set, or a television bigger than an average computer monitor are all beyond my means. That those major sales bring the unattainable items to a level of affordability is what drives all of those people to line up and storm through doors on Black Friday.<br />
Those are people teetering on or even below the poverty level, desperate for comfort in their homes. To point to them as a reason to start an anti-consumerism movement is just another form of social shaming. Those aren't the people who would benefit from a minimalist life. They can't afford to do with less.<br />
<cite><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2016/07/18/opinion/the-class-politics-of-decluttering.html">Ayumi Takahashi</a></cite></p>
</blockquote>

<h4 id="footnotes">Footnotes</h4>

<div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
  <ol>
    <li id="fn:1" role="doc-endnote">
      <p>Not sure what that is, sounds like "TV radio" to me. <a href="#fnref:1" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
  </ol>
</div>

          <hr /><p><a href="mailto:hello@minutestomidnight.co.uk?subject=Minimalism%20as%20a%20product">Reply via email</a></p>]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2024 22:13:55 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://minutestomidnight.co.uk/blog/minimalism-as-a-product/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">https://minutestomidnight.co.uk/blog/minimalism-as-a-product/</guid>
        <category>Minimalism</category>
        <category>Sustainability</category>
        <category>Usa</category>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Looking from a distance</title>
        <author>hello@minutestomidnight.co.uk (Simone Silvestroni)</author>
        <description><![CDATA[
          A draft of this post languished in my computer for longer than two months. Pessimistic, self-deprecating, depressing, bad. So, I wiped it out, and started from scratch.
          <hr>
          <p>Several months after returning to the UK — back from the 3-year-long limbo spent in my home country — the endless ruminations on the pain of having gone back to Italy brought me to a simple conclusion: it actually was a good thing.</p>

<p>On a gut level, the immediate consideration is that I was given time and distance to see Britain from afar, appreciating the many positives that the <em>Brexit years</em> had corroded. Being able to revisit a long-time experience with a different and more honest point of view fills me with gratitude. Or, as my wife aptly wrote, <a href="https://silviamaggidesign.com/personal/home-again/">it made us realise where home is</a>.</p>

<p>The deepest positive, though, one that will likely have long-term ramifications, was the chance to reconnect with people, both family and friends. Despite the angst of constantly being a guest in someone else's house for such a long time, I didn't realise until the very end how I loved spending time with important people from my past, dear friends that I thought I had lost touch with. We got to spend many months with three of them, in one case sharing the same apartment where we had been living together for six years, two decades ago.</p>

<p>We're adults now, of course everything feels different. A communal life is not an aspiration anymore, and adapting wasn't straightforward. Inevitably, leaving our home country in 2011 had brought the obvious inability to share the same cultural mindset. Nevertheless, I enjoyed the feeling of a sometimes awkward newfound connection, more than its opposite.</p>

<p>In another case, being somewhat forced to share the same space carried something that I now see with some degree of nostalgia: long deep chats under the summer moon, a stone's throw from the sea, with the evening waves quietly crashing on the beach. Or cycling 10 kilometres back and forth, in the pine forest, crossing the canal on the old ferry boat, and eat amazing meals with my family while laughing at their well-known old tales. That was <em>precious</em>, almost like a second chance.</p>

<p>My fucked-up home country, messy, frustrating, often incomprehensible Italy. I loved you for those bittersweet moments.</p>

          <hr /><p><a href="mailto:hello@minutestomidnight.co.uk?subject=Looking%20from%20a%20distance">Reply via email</a></p>]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 22:50:14 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://minutestomidnight.co.uk/blog/looking-from-a-distance/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">https://minutestomidnight.co.uk/blog/looking-from-a-distance/</guid>
        <category>Featured</category>
        <category>Italy</category>
        <category>Personal</category>
        <category>Uk</category>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Good news</title>
        <author>hello@minutestomidnight.co.uk (Simone Silvestroni)</author>
        <description><![CDATA[
          It appears as if more people are realising how actively listening to music is something we should have never stopped doing.
          <hr>
          <p>My friend Leigh of <a href="https://sidesister.bandcamp.com/">SideSister</a> shared an article from <em>The Guardian</em>, titled <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/music/2022/sep/27/theres-endless-choice-but-youre-not-listening-fans-quitting-spotify-to-save-their-love-of-music"><em>"There's endless choice, but you're not listening": fans quitting Spotify to save their love of music</em></a>. Might be a drop in the ocean, but I love that a few more people are making the conscious decision of leaving a commodified and passive way to experience music.</p>

<p>Whenever I say that I don't have an account on any of the streaming platforms, I usually get asked <em>how do I listen to music</em> — almost like if streaming is the only way. The answer is easy: the same as it was in 1985. I have a library, a <em>personal</em> one, which I can access from my devices. I might not have a record player anymore, and even if I still own a working Sony cassette deck, I might not have cassettes around. However, all the music that I bought throughout the years, together with my wife's, have been ripped to a digital format, carefully catalogued in a small portable SSD drive, and connected to our home network.</p>

<p>There's no corporation to tell us what to like, or define the right mood for the day. We do that ourselves. We decide on what to listen, and if it's not entire albums, maybe it's a playlist made earlier in our player — <a href="http://swinsian.com">Swinsian</a> on macOS. Might even be a new one built on purpose for some occasion, a bit like a mixtape. It still feels like building a real connection.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>I like music because it's a communal artistic practice, and anything that I can do that allows me to listen to music in a way that connects me with either the artists or my friends, that's what I want to be involved with. Spotify and streaming in general just has absolutely no connection with that relationship at all.
<cite>Jeff Tobias</cite></p>
</blockquote>

<div class="iframe-container">
	<iframe title="Video" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/IzQwbRdh5Ts?rel=0" allow="fullscreen; picture-in-picture" loading="lazy" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
	</iframe>
</div>

          <hr /><p><a href="mailto:hello@minutestomidnight.co.uk?subject=Good%20news">Reply via email</a></p>]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 21:35:45 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://minutestomidnight.co.uk/blog/good-news/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">https://minutestomidnight.co.uk/blog/good-news/</guid>
        <category>Music</category>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Leaving Netlify</title>
        <author>hello@minutestomidnight.co.uk (Simone Silvestroni)</author>
        <description><![CDATA[
          Tomorrow marks the first week after migrating all the websites I share with my wife <a href='https://silviamaggidesign.com'>Silvia</a>, from Netlify to <a href='https://www.mythic-beasts.com'>Mythic Beasts</a>. Very happy about the quick transition, and grateful to <a href='https://www.thisdaysportion.com'>Leon Paternoster</a> for the brilliant suggestion. Here's something I've noticed since.
          <hr>
          <p>In a similar fashion to how people can't remember phone numbers anymore, by delegating production build and deployment to Netlify, I progressively lost parts of a technical knowledge that comes with habits. While their free tier allowed me to quickly move away from WordPress at no cost, it undoubtedly contributed to the loss of control over how I manage the last stage of web design. Ironically, the main reason for leaving Automattic four years ago was indeed the will to regain control over my source code.</p>

<p>Years ago I used the powerful <a href="https://capistranorb.com/">Ruby gem Capistrano</a> to deploy complex websites for large clients. It was the opposite of delegating the process, as I was fully in control from start to finish. I could customise the workflow by using SSH commands, managing different environments between development, staging, and production, filter files and more. I hadn't realised how Netlify more or less removed that kind of granular responsibility.</p>

<p>An immediate result was the embarrassing rush to find my old code, which helped discovering a way to consolidate Netlify's custom <code>.toml</code> configurations into a well constructed <code>.htaccess</code> file. After refactoring my entire dev/production workflow, I now feel way more confident. Once again, Silicon Valley had convinced me that convenience should be the path to do more tasks in less time. However, designing for the web is not like using a machine to wash the laundry. It's more like cooking: takes knowledge, experience, a bit of artistry. Also, it takes the right amount of <em>time</em>.</p>

          <hr /><p><a href="mailto:hello@minutestomidnight.co.uk?subject=Leaving%20Netlify">Reply via email</a></p>]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 00:26:40 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://minutestomidnight.co.uk/blog/leaving-netlify/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">https://minutestomidnight.co.uk/blog/leaving-netlify/</guid>
        <category>Internet</category>
        <category>Web development</category>
        <category>Workflow</category>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>The Accounts Graveyard</title>
        <author>hello@minutestomidnight.co.uk (Simone Silvestroni)</author>
        <description><![CDATA[
          A personal process of disinvesting from the corporate internet, started last year, is speeding up considerably in 2024. It’s fuelled by a desire of reducing digital noise, and severing my contacts with a tech world that isn’t appealing anymore.
          <hr>
          <p>After deleting an old WordPress account last week, I opened my Bitwarden password vault to check on the preposterous number of login entries — around 460. Inspired by the <a href="https://killedbygoogle.com">Google Graveyard</a>, I started a side project: collecting names of major corporations that I've had an account with for years, and that I want to rid of.</p>

<p>Not going to list <em>all</em> the two hundreds and fifty accounts that I've erased, nor complain about the <a href="https://dictionary.cambridge.org/dictionary/english/byzantine">bizantine</a> manoeuvres put in place by corporations in order to prevent people from leaving — that's their problem. Far from being yet another frustrated post on the growth-at-all-costs culture of the capitalistic internet, I want to briefly analyse a few deletions, and why they helped me feeling lighter and quieter.</p>

<h2 id="music">Music</h2>

<p>Nobody have ever reached out by saying they were interested in knowing more, after finding my music on <em>Spotify</em>. Since this is by design, I removed all the music and deleted both my personal and artist accounts. Same as with <a href="https://minutestomidnight.co.uk/blog/leaving-soundcloud/"><em>SoundCloud</em></a>, it feels pointless to scatter songs over centralised online silos. The sanest direction of travel from now on is to follow the principles of <a href="https://beyourownplatform.site">#BeYourOwnPlatform</a>.</p>

<h2 id="the-large-ones">The large ones</h2>

<p>I stopped ruminating over my past participation with large conglomerates. I'm just glad that now I don't get noise from <em>Facebook</em>, <em>Instagram</em>, <em>Twitter</em>, <em>Reddit</em>, <em>Medium</em>, <em>Microsoft</em>, and <em>Adobe</em>. Happy about not spreading <em>Mailchimp</em> tracking codes into people's inboxes, I've never went anywhere near <em>Substack</em> either. Once I manage to refurbish my Android phone with an independent <em>Google</em>-free ROM, I'm also gonna axe the ex-search-now-ads giant.</p>

<h2 id="automattic">Automattic</h2>

<p>Four years ago, when I decided to leave WordPress, I didn't do it in spite of any company shenanigans: I simply wanted to simplify my personal site. While it's true that I've never liked its CEO and co-founder, the recent pile-up of multiple controversies pushed me to delete accounts with <em>wordpress.com</em>, <em>wordpress.org</em>, <em>PocketCast</em>, and consequently the now useless <em>WP Rocket</em> and <em>Yoast</em>. <em>Tumblr</em> had been in the graveyard for some time.</p>

<h2 id="vc-funded-vultures">VC-funded vultures</h2>

<p>Cut ties with <em>Uber</em>, <em>Netlify</em>, <em>AirBnB</em>, <em>Cloudflare</em>, <em>Zapier</em>, and many more.</p>

<h2 id="the-pointless-ones">The pointless ones</h2>

<p>Whether because they don't make sense to me anymore, or due to some enlightened management decision to follow the AI <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Trolley_problem">trolley problem</a>, I quit holding hands with <em>Mozilla</em>, <em>Deviantart</em>, <em>Stack Overflow</em>, <em>Atlassian</em>, <em>Trello</em>, <em>Discord</em>, <em>Eventbrite</em>, <em>Meetup</em>, <em>Figma</em>, <em>Klarna</em>, <em>Patreon</em>, <em>Vimeo</em>, <em>WeTransfer</em>.</p>

<h2 id="final-thoughts">Final thoughts</h2>

<p>The above amounts to a tiny percentage of the culling. A sheer number of deletions are confined in the extremely fragmented world of sound design. Every single audio plug-in depends on an inefficient online account, whether the software is paid or free, so I moved away from that world a while ago, to consolidate my efforts around a few tiny (and one big) companies.</p>

<p>A heartfelt mention of honour goes to <em>Avid</em>. The privacy request I sent on 4 December 2023 through their official privacy channel still has to be processed. Two months later I asked what the wait was for, so they assigned a request ID to my reply, answering after a week by saying "This is a duplicate question about a previous request". I'll wait.</p>

          <hr /><p><a href="mailto:hello@minutestomidnight.co.uk?subject=The%20Accounts%20Graveyard">Reply via email</a></p>]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 22:27:41 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://minutestomidnight.co.uk/blog/the-accounts-graveyard/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">https://minutestomidnight.co.uk/blog/the-accounts-graveyard/</guid>
        <category>Internet</category>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>The snake eating its own tail</title>
        <author>hello@minutestomidnight.co.uk (Simone Silvestroni)</author>
        <description><![CDATA[
          There once was a serpent who only traveled in one direction, always forward, never backward. Until one day, the serpent came upon a demon. The demon cursed the serpent, driving him insane, causing him to eat his own tail.
          <hr>
          <p>For a while I've been mulling over a distinct feeling, the sudden realisation that I've been dwelling in too much negativity. Not sure for how long it's been going on, but I'm certain of the loop it generates: like an <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ouroboros">ouroboros</a>, while absorbing gloominess elsewhere, I've been contributing with my own feelings of deep despondency.</p>

<p>I see human affairs kindly showing what we're capable of, on a daily basis. However, no one needs to constantly keep soaking in fury, frustration, and generalised pessimism. After the decision to stay away from mainstream news, and delete all corporate social media, why am I still so attached to this Orwellian need to vent my two minutes of hate on a daily basis? Whether it's me or Mastodon — or better, the act of being exposed to a mostly pessimistic barrage of short statements from all over the world — it's a cycle that I'm going to break.</p>

          <hr /><p><a href="mailto:hello@minutestomidnight.co.uk?subject=The%20snake%20eating%20its%20own%20tail">Reply via email</a></p>]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 21:01:03 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://minutestomidnight.co.uk/blog/the-snake-eating-its-own-tail/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">https://minutestomidnight.co.uk/blog/the-snake-eating-its-own-tail/</guid>
        <category>Personal</category>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Living in a corporate bubble</title>
        <author>hello@minutestomidnight.co.uk (Simone Silvestroni)</author>
        <description><![CDATA[
          Sanctimonious post about something that, strangely enough, just occurred to me: normal people can easily turn into soulless sellers, casually dropping ridiculous corporate jargon while taking money out of the same group they call <em>community</em>.
          <hr>
          <p>Yesterday I watched a few videos from well-known professionals in the music production field, which left me stunned. Not sure if it was the language, or the way they were taking the topics so seriously, but the struggle to properly understand was real. They were waffling on about the reasons for having failed to release new videos in 2024, or what upload schedule works best, or ways to complement their income with online courses, Patreon, up to bragging about their considerable YouTube earnings in the name of transparency.</p>

<p>Aware of the fact that I can't possibly understand what's involved with maintaining social media accounts with millions of subscribers, I felt so alienated that I jotted down a few key phrases out of their influencers' vocabulary:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>The <em>audience</em> is everything.<br /><br />
The hole in the video release schedule caused the channel to suffer.<br /><br />
I failed to keep momentum for the channel.<br /><br />
It's going to take months to recover.<br /><br />
I don't have a buffer of videos.<br /><br />
The biggest <em>YouTubers</em> have upload schedules, they release videos at certain times of the day.<br /><br />
I'm a <em>YouTuber</em>, it's not an hobby anymore.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>How many people actually live in that sort of bubble? One of them has started paying a small team of employees, so they can <em>treble</em> the amount of videos for the channel. Referring to the fact that there's been a flurry of famous "YouTubers" leaving the platform or taking a hiatus — apparently there's a burnout crisis in the "creator economy" — they unironically stated <em>I'm a content creator</em>. What does that even mean?</p>

<p>They all seem to have a few things in common: beside the obligatory <code>exaggerated-idiotic-face-glowing-on-the-side-of-huge-clickbait-title</code> YouTube thumbnail, they talk <em>an awful lot</em> about themselves while insisting on the assumption that they're running a <em>community</em>. Of course, this requires applying several degrees of gaslighting to cover the indisputable fact that they're making money off it, while contributing to the ads-driven corporate web that has turned the internet to shit.</p>

<p>Yeah, I really am this naîve about people getting rich by exploiting social media platforms, probably because I've never believed in setting up a lifestyle on tools that are ephemeral by default. Concluding on this self-righteous half rant, I'd like to quote Jennifer Del Gato, who perfectly encapsuled the same concepts a few days ago in her entry for <a href="https://manuelmoreale.com/indieweb-carnival-digital-relationships">this month's IndieWeb Carnival</a>:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>If you choose to monetize your online presence, which is your prerogative, then don't mistake your relationship with other Netizens as being a "community." A parasocial relationship between an influencer and her audience isn't a community, it's a <em>fandom</em>.<cite><a href="https://devastatia.com/on-influencers-and-parasocial-relationships">On Influencers and Parasocial Relationships</a></cite></p>
</blockquote>

          <hr /><p><a href="mailto:hello@minutestomidnight.co.uk?subject=Living%20in%20a%20corporate%20bubble">Reply via email</a></p>]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2024 11:23:10 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://minutestomidnight.co.uk/blog/living-in-a-corporate-bubble/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">https://minutestomidnight.co.uk/blog/living-in-a-corporate-bubble/</guid>
        <category>Internet</category>
        <category>Social media</category>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Read later</title>
        <author>hello@minutestomidnight.co.uk (Simone Silvestroni)</author>
        <description><![CDATA[
          My latest post generated a few emails from people suggesting alternatives to my semi-manual Instapaper solution. The back-and-forth convinced me to describe how I use read later services.
          <hr>
          <p>I knew about the suggested solutions already, so why didn't I choose either of the open source <a href="https://wallabag.org/">Wallabag</a> or <a href="https://omnivore.app/">Omnivore</a>? As I said to Gabriel Augendre and Peter Hogg, who correctly assumed I'd be interested in owning more of my data, I don’t use read later services like I usually see other people doing. To me they’re not bookmarks, or something that I might want to go back to in the future. It’s a short-time transitory place where I put articles and videos that I am going to read and watch within a week. If I really like something, I save it in PDF, markdown, or mp4 to my computer.</p>

<p>Instapaper is discrete, quiet, well designed. I like exporting articles in ePub and load them on my Kobo: the manual process helps with the feeling of having some sort of personal magazine, that I can then read at my pace. Lastly, I'm in a place where I’m not keen on tinkering, and self-hosting takes time that I don't currently have.</p>

          <hr /><p><a href="mailto:hello@minutestomidnight.co.uk?subject=Read%20later">Reply via email</a></p>]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 18:09:45 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://minutestomidnight.co.uk/blog/read-later/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">https://minutestomidnight.co.uk/blog/read-later/</guid>
        <category>Internet</category>
        <category>Personal</category>
        <category>Software</category>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Instapaper on my Kobo</title>
        <author>hello@minutestomidnight.co.uk (Simone Silvestroni)</author>
        <description><![CDATA[
          Once again, whenever I favour convenience over substance, my experience does not improve.
          <hr>
          <p>Erasing my Pocket account a few weeks ago was an easy choice. Ever since Mozilla morphed it into yet another algorithmic-based attention seeker, I couldn't stand the product. Went straight back to <a href="https://www.instapaper.com">Instapaper</a> — a mature, simple, elegant reading application that's not trying to force unsolicited crap onto me.</p>

<p>What's this got to do with my Kobo? As it happens, <a href="https://help.kobo.com/hc/en-us/articles/360017763753-Use-the-Pocket-App-with-your-Kobo-eReader">Pocket is integrated in its operating system</a>, so every time I saved an article for later, it showed up on the ereader. Reading articles and posts on such a device is a much better experience compared to a phone or a laptop. It was <em>convenient</em>.</p>

<p>Today I discovered that Instapaper has a download function which includes epub among the formats: it's fast and looks amazing. Sure, it needs to be copied to the Kobo via a USB cable, but if the goal was to be able to read my articles offline in a beautiful stripped down format on a relaxing device, I call it a complete success.</p>

          <hr /><p><a href="mailto:hello@minutestomidnight.co.uk?subject=Instapaper%20on%20my%20Kobo">Reply via email</a></p>]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2024 20:07:59 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://minutestomidnight.co.uk/blog/instapaper-on-my-kobo/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">https://minutestomidnight.co.uk/blog/instapaper-on-my-kobo/</guid>
        <category>Internet</category>
        <category>Personal</category>
        <category>Software</category>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>